

PERSONAL PROFILE

Python Developer with 2.10 years of experience in building data-intensive applications, overcoming complex architectural, and scalability issues in diverse industries. Proficient in predictive modeling, data processing, as well as scripting languages, including Python. Capable of creating, developing, testing, and deploying highly adaptive diverse services to translate business and functional qualifications into substantial deliverables.

EMPLOYMENT DETAIL

Currently working as a Software Engineer with Calsoft Private Limited, Pune since Jan 2019 -Present

CERTIFICATIONS

- Machine Learning
 Stanford University- Coursera
- Introduction to TensorFlow for Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, and Deep Learning
- Python Data Structures
- Using Python to Access Web Data

AWARDS

Client Appreciation Award, 2021

SKILLS

- Python
- AI/ML
- Tensorflow
- NLP
- FastAPI
- Jenkins
- Networking
- Docker
- SOL
- Git
- Postman
- Pandas and Numpy
- Object Oriented Programming

TECHNICAL SUMMARY

- Engineering professional with 2.10 years of experience in Software development.
- Leading in the development of applications/tools using Python and Machine Learning.
- Worked on several python packages like NumPy, Pandas, Tensorflow, Transformers, OpenCV, FastAPI, etc.
- Experience in Design, Development, Testing, Automation, Enhancement, and Maintenance of Applications and Tools.
- Good knowledge in various phases of SDLC Requirement Analysis, Design, Development, and Testing on various Development and Enhancement Projects.
- Good Experience in Python development of multithreaded applications in a Linux Environment.
- Have flexibility and ability to learn and use new technologies and also to work in a team environment as wells as independently to get things done.
- Experience with Version Control, ideally GIT,
- PycharmDevelopment of several Python APIs and harassers that works both in Linux and windows

CONTACT

8962775625

dipeshpal17@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/dipesh-paul

github.com/Dipeshpal

ww dipeshpal.in

M dipeshpal17.medium.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

Calsoft Pvt.Ltd, Development Engineer

AUG 2019 - PRESENT

- Build predictive models using various machine learning tools to automate the ticketing system.
- Develop algorithms using Natural Language Processing and Deep Learning models.
- Design algorithms for predicting the pricing of the product using Deep Learning models and deployed with FastAPI, Docker.

Calsoft Pvt.Ltd, Development Engineer Intern

JUN 2019 - JULY 2019

- Worked on solving complicated problems and worked on POCs.
- Created CNN models for the POCs.

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITY

- Involvement in various aspects of the software development lifecycle including design implementation, unit testing, deployment.
- Resolve complex problems with custom-designed neural networks.
- Producing clean, efficient code based on specifications.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science, 2019. Acropolis Institute of Tech. & Research, Indore

PROJECTS

• Title: Price Analysis with Scraping

Scraped data for pricing strategies for laptops, desktops, and gaming devices and build an ML model for price prediction. Collected data from various E-Commerce and OEM websites across the globe.

Technology Used: Python, FastAPI, AI/ML, Tensorflow, Jenkins, Docker, Scrapy, Transformers.

• Title: Ticket Analyzer

Automate the ticketing tool, with the help of Machine Learning. Where technologies like NLP and Wikipediatrained ULMfit Fastai models are used to fine-tune our Ticket dataset and to find out the ticket and assigned person.

Technology Used: Python, Kafka, Docker, FastAPI, AI/ML, Fastai.

• Title: Oil Price Prediction

The goal is to analyze the growth of markets like refineries, stock, etc) with the help of user reviews, sentiment, and comments. By using Fastai and Keras with Facebook's Roberta, LSTM, ULMFit, etc. to fine-tune the model.

Technology Used: Python, Kafka, Plotly, Docker, AI/ML with Fastai and Tensorflow

• Title: Avatar Generator

Create avatars for human faces for the portfolio. Trained the model using the images dataset of approximately 143,000 images of Humans and Cartoons. Many different architectures of Neural Networks, Deep Convolutional GANs (Style GAN), CNN, UNet to train the model.

Technology used: Python, AI/ML, Tensorflow, OpenCV, DZone

• Title: Steel Defect Detection

Detection of steel sheet defects needs to find using Machine Learning, this automation approach leads the industry to high-quality steel production. Build the custom CNN model with U-Net and using Keras. This automation is run as a web app build with FastAPI.

Technology Used: Python, FastAPI, AI/ML, Fastai, and Keras